{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Most spoilage bacteria grow at", "opta": "acidic pH", "optb": "alkaline pH", "optc": "neutral pH", "optd": "any of the pH", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The microbiological examination of coliform bacteria in foods preferably use", "opta": "MacConkey broth", "optb": "violet Red Bile agar", "optc": "eosine Methylene blue agar", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following acid will have higher bacteriostatic effect at a given pH?", "opta": "Acetic acid", "optb": "Tartaric acid", "optc": "Citric acid", "optd": "Maleic acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true for the thermal resistance of the bacterial cells?", "opta": "Cocci are usually more resistant than rods", "optb": "Higher the optimal and maximal temperatures for growth, higher the resistance", "optc": "Bacteria that clump considerably or form capsules are difficult to kill", "optd": "Cells low in lipid content are harder to kill than other cells", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Water activity can act as", "opta": "an intrinsic factor determining the likelihood of microbial proliferation", "optb": "a processing factor", "optc": "an extrinsic factor", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enumeration of microorganism refers to", "opta": "either spiral plating, pour plate or spread plate of a food suspension on to a suitable selective agar, or non-selective plate, depending on the test", "optb": "either spiral plating, pour plate or spread plate of a food suspension on to a suitable selective agar", "optc": "non-selective plating, depending on the test", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The different ACC's between food categories reflect the", "opta": "expected level of contamination of the raw material", "optb": "potential for microbial growth during storage", "optc": "potential shelf life", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Examination of the presence / absence of organisms refers to", "opta": "incubation of a food suspension in an enrichment medium followed by inoculation on to a suitable selective medium.", "optb": "incubation of a food suspension in an enrichment medium followed by inoculation on to a non-selective medium.", "optc": "incubation of a food suspension in an enrichment medium", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plate count of bacteria in foods generally use the plating medium consisting of", "opta": "peptone, yeast extract, glucose, sodium chloride, agar and distilled water", "optb": "yeast extract, glucose, sodium chloride, agar and distilled water", "optc": "peptone, glucose, sodium chloride, agar and distilled water", "optd": "peptone, yeast extract, glucose, sodium chloride and distilled water", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the intrinsic factors for the microbial growth?", "opta": "pH", "optb": "Moisture", "optc": "Oxidation-Reduction Potential", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Yeast and mould count determination requires-", "opta": "nutrient agar", "optb": "acidified potato glucose agar", "optc": "MacConkey agar", "optd": "violet Red Bile agar", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time temperature combination for HTST paterurization of 71.1\u00b0C for 15 sec is selected on the basis of", "opta": "Coxiella Burnetii", "optb": "E. coli", "optc": "B. subtilis", "optd": "C. botulinum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Aerobic Colony Count (ACC), is also known as", "opta": "Total viable count (TVC)", "optb": "Aerobic plate count (APC)", "optc": "Standard plate count (SPC)", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true about ISO 2002 method for Salmonella detection?", "opta": "Selenite cystine (SC) broth is replaced by Muller Kauffmann tetrathionate novobiocin broth (MKTTn)", "optb": "Rappaport Vassiliadis (RV) broth has been replaced by Rappaport Vassiliadis Soya (RVS) broth", "optc": "XLD is the first isolation medium rather than BGA", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Suspected colonies of Staphylococcus aureus when grown on Baird-Parker medium shall show", "opta": "coagulase activity", "optb": "protease activity", "optc": "catalase activity", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A psychrophilic halophile would be a microbe that prefers", "opta": "cold temperatures and increased amounts of salt", "optb": "warm temperatures and increased amounts of pressure", "optc": "cold temperatures and the absence of oxygen", "optd": "warm temperatures and increased amounts of acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "NaCl can act as", "opta": "antagonist at optimal concentrations", "optb": "synergistically if added in excess of optimum level", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}